# IQBAL ANWAR

# FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

## PERSONAL PROFILE

As an applied math student turned Software Engineer, my statistical analysis knowledge combined with functional programming builds quality, scalable applications.

Driven to build useful software, I simplify consumers' complicated routines. With my experience in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Java, I write efficient and elegant programming solutions.

# **SKILLS**

**Front end**: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript (ES6), React.js, Mocha & Chai, Jest

**Back-end**: Java, Spring Boot (MVC), JUnit, SQL (Postgres), NoSQL (MongoDB),

**Tools**: AWS EC2 & S3, Docker, Heroku, Atlassian JIRA, Figma

Methodologies: Test Driven
Development, Unit Testing, Version
Control & Git, Responsive Design, OOP,
CRUD, AJAX, RESTful API

*Miscellaneous*: Matlab, Microsoft Office Applications (PowerPoint/Excel/Access), AnyDesk for remote work

# **CONTACT**

- ◆ igbalaanwar@gmail.com
- ♦ linkedin.com/in/iqbalaanwar
- ◆ github.com/iqbalanwar
- ◆ iqbalanwar.github.io

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## American Express Developer Academy

GENERAL ASSEMBLY, AUG 2019 TO NOV 2019

- One of 25 from 1200 applicants accepted into a sponsored, 12-week General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive
- Created full-stack web applications in collaborative teams using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, AJAX, Node.js, Java, Spring, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB
- Implemented several different methodologies, including Object-Oriented Programming, building CRUD and RESTful APIs, and using an Agile workflow
- Learned Git for workflow management, Docker for code (container) management, and SCRUM for project management
- Aligned with industry standards for programming through consistent documentation and test-driven development

### Software Developer

MOI INC, JAN 2017 TO DEC 2017

- Built a responsive website using HTML/CSS/jQuery, Bootstrap for front-end; Ruby on Rails and MongoDB for back-end
- Managed workflow using GitHub to share code and website materials
- · Planned goals and deadlines for a development team using JIRA

#### Instructor

OPTIMUM TUTORIAL, JAN 2014 TO JULY 2015

- Coordinated with schools, other instructors, and teachers to develop teaching methods and integrated instruction best suited for students
- Guided students in their studies, across several subjects and grades. As a result, more than 20 students received above 1800 on their SAT

# **PROJECTS**

#### Day-To-Day

CALENDAR APP

- **Description:** Calendar app to manage upcoming events and scheduling, based on day and month
- Tech Stack: React.js, Spring Boot, Docker, AWS

#### Officey

REDDIT-LIKE WEBSITE IN HOMAGE TO "THE OFFICE"

- **Description:** Sign-up to make profiles like The Office characters, along with create posts and comments
- Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Spring Boot

#### Pixel Art

PAINT APP

- Description: Paint on a canvas with a color of your choice, and save the last three colors used
- Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

# **EDUCATION**

City College of New York CUNY, Sept 2015 - May 2019

Major: Applied Mathematics Minor: Computer Science

General Assembly, Aug 2019 - Nov 2019

Immersive: American Express Developer Academy